<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: george | ]]></title>
  <link href="//george/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T08:27:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[{"name"=>"Richard Perry", "email"=>"richard@perrymail.me.uk", "github"=>"richardp2", "twitter"=>"richard_p2"}]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[George's Second Year]]></title>
    <link href="/george/second-year/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T18:00:16Z</updated>
    <id>/george/second-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images//George-Rosies-Birthday-2014-9194.jpg"><img src="/images/thumbs//George-Rosies-Birthday-2014-9194.jpg" alt="George &amp; Rosie's Birthday" class="alignleft" /></a>George is now another year older so how has the second year gone? Well, it’s been very different to the first year! Having recovered from his illness over the new year, George got back on his feet and hasn’t really stopped since. Rosie has had to open the eyes in the back of her head to try to keep up with him. Unfortunately, just before his first birthday, we discovered George has nut allergy so that has been interesting, considering we used to cook everything in groundnut oil and peanut butter was our favourite breakfast addition. Nevermind, we have adapted quite well I think and George hasn’t had any problems this year so it’s all good :-).</p>

<p>Over the year he has definitely developed his own personality and he has grown up so much! He is yet to start speaking, but he does say a number of words now and can sign sentences (although he doesn’t bother very often). We have had a National Trust membership for the last year so we’ve visited lots of different old houses and gardens giving George plenty of opportunity to run and play outside, and he seems to have loved every minute of it.</p>

<p>Here is a list of the key events in his second year.</p>

<ul>
  <li>07 February – George completed his first full year in this world</li>
  <li>26 February – George gets tooth number 9</li>
  <li>01 March – George’s 10th tooth breaks through</li>
  <li>04 March – George gets his 11th tooth</li>
  <li>15 March – George learnt to clap</li>
  <li>01 – 07 April George’s First Visit Abroad (Paris &amp; Disneyland)</li>
  <li>01 June - Hamleys Photoshoot</li>
  <li>07 June – George gets 2 new teeth</li>
  <li>08 June – Venture Photography Photoshoot &amp; George escapes his cot</li>
  <li>26 June – Georges Allergy test – waste of time!</li>
  <li>12 September – George given his first training chopsticks!</li>
  <li>26 November – George reached 50 signs!</li>
  <li>03 December – All George’s teeth are now through!</li>
  <li>07 February 2014 – George now weighs 11.7kg and is  82cm tall</li>
</ul>

<p>Now, we’re looking forward to another great year discovering who our little man is.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[George's First Year]]></title>
    <link href="/george/first-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-27T21:29:52Z</updated>
    <id>/george/first-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/george/first-year/attachment/georges-first-birthday/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/02/IMG_2904-150x150.jpg" alt="George's First Birthday" /></a>George is now a year old so I thought it might be time for a bit of reflection on how the first year has gone :-). For Rosie &amp; I it has been a bit of a rollercoaster ride, but I think we’ve been very lucky. George has generally been good as gold since the day he was born. Don’t get me wrong, he cries, screams and tests the boundaries just like any other kid, but I think we may have had things a little easier than most.  Most of the time he seems to be contented and happy, but he is definitely learning the art of crying for attention! We’ll have to keep that one in check I think. George also seems to be developing physically very fast. Granted he is short (but who does that surprise with Rosie &amp; I for parents!!) but he went from being a generally stationary baby to walking in no time at all! It’s brilliant to see the progression and I am really enjoying the fact he is so mobile most of the time, although sometimes it would be nice if he would stay put for longer than 1 second! Here is a list of the milestones he has reached in his first 12 months.</p>

<h3 id="milestones">Milestones</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>07 February 2012 - George was born :-D at 13:47 weighing 3.48kg (7lb 11oz)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>09 - 12 April 2012 - First holiday (Cornwall)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>08 May 2012 - First laughed</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>25 May 2012 - First night camping (Portcullis Camp)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>01 June 2012 - First flight (to Jersey)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>09 June 2012 - First sat up</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>July 2012 - First walked with help</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>18 July 2012 - First sat unaided</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>19 July 2012 - First tooth</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>21 July 2012 - First crawled</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>29 September 2012 - First stood unaided</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>23 December 2012 - First walked alone</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>We are still really enjoying being parents, even with the occasional sleepless night, public temper tantrum etc. I am extremely glad I made the decision to move to my <a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/a-new-start/">new job</a> because it has meant I have been able to spend a lot more time with George than I would have done otherwise. It’s been a great year and I’m thoroughly looking forward to what this year will bring :-D.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[George Goes Swimming]]></title>
    <link href="/george/george-goes-swimming/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T22:47:03Z</updated>
    <id>/george/george-goes-swimming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/06/Blue-Island-Plane.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/06/Blue-Island-Plane-e1338676449756-150x150.jpg" alt="Blue Island Plane" /></a>The Jubilee weekend has brought us to Jersey to visit George’s Auntie Liz (Rosie’s sister) &amp; Uncle Steve. We started the weekend on Friday evening with George’s first flight which was a 19 seat ‘toy’ plane. I don’t think I’ve been so excited about a flight since the first flight I remember going on myself too many years ago. It was both exciting and scary at the same time because George’s reaction to this flight could affect our future traveling quite considerably.</p>

<p><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/06/IMG_9263-150x150.jpg" alt="George Goes Swimming" /></p>

<p>Well, as usual, George missed the excitement through sleep! At this rate people will start to think he does nothing but sleep! We arrived in Jersey on time after a very uneventful flight (thankfully) and were taken swiftly out for dinner. At this point George decided it was a good time to wake up and let the world know he existed, although not for long, we still managed to have a good evening :-).</p>

<p><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/06/IMG_9274-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This morning Auntie Liz took us to the pool where she works so that George could have his first proper swimming lesson. We stopped at the fish market on the way to the pool to pick up food for our barbecue and, no surprise, George slept the whole time. Liz arranged for us to have some time alone in the pool, which was absolutely brilliant. It was great to have his first experience in a swimming pool in private. Rosie and I were fully expecting him to scream on first dip, but quite to the contrary, he seemed very contented in the water :-). Excellent!</p>

<p><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/06/IMG_9292-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz &amp; George" /></p>

<p>We swam him around the pool for almost half an hour before making the difficult decision to fully submerge him. It was at this point that the fun stopped. George screamed his head off as soon as he resurfaced, but we’re not too sure whether that was all down to the submersion or the fact he was getting hungry from all the exercise.</p>

<p>Ever since we got home, George has been sleeping with short interludes for food. I think his Auntie Liz has properly tired him out!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[George's First Hike]]></title>
    <link href="/george/georges-first-hike/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-01T11:55:38Z</updated>
    <id>/george/georges-first-hike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0720.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0720-150x150.jpg" alt="George's First Mountain_0720" /></a>Yesteday we decided it was about time George got to see a real mountain so instead of taking the easy option and going up to Mynydd Maen, we went up to Storey Arms with a view to taking a walk up to Pen-y-Fan. Obviously we were well aware of the potential difficulties of taking a 7½ week old baby up a mountain, so we dragged along a good friend of ours, Stewart Cunningham (<a href="http://diaryofascoutleader.blogspot.co.uk/">Diary of a Scout Leader</a>). We arrived at the Storey Arms car park at about lunch time, I strapped George to my chest and off we went. It was a much cooler day than it has been so thankfully we didn’t have to fight with the heat or the sun, just the walking :-).</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0726.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0726-150x150.jpg" alt="George's First Mountain_0726" /></a>About half way up the route to Corn Du we noticed that the cloud level was starting to drop and it wasn’t looking too hopeful, but we soldiered on while George slept happily in his sling with the proviso that if the weather started to turn we would call it a day. It was a fairly slow walk, but that probably has a lot to do with the fact that both Rosie and myself haven’t done a lot of proper walking recently, as well as Rosie having only given birth to George 7½ weeks ago! The last hundred metres or so of climbing up Corn Du are quite steep so things got a little more difficult, especially due to the fact George had decided it was time to wake up. By the time we got to the top George was hungry, and the altitude was starting to bother him so Rosie fed him at 873m above sea level just as the clouds fully closed in around us making visibility severely limited.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0721.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/04/IMG_0721-150x150.jpg" alt="George's First Mountain_0721" /></a>By the time George was ready to go on, the weather had definitely taken a turn for the worse so unfortunately we took the decision to turn back and skip Pen-y-Fan for today. It was a bit disappointing having to turn around when we were so close, but on the other hand we got to the top of Corn Du with a 7½ week old baby in March!!! :-) I think George had a good day even if he was asleep for most of it.</p>

<p>View <a href="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps/ms?msid=215094904436363903208.0004bc9c9ff4aa5f54060&amp;msa=0&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;ll=51.877445,-3.441124&amp;spn=0.037091,0.090122&amp;z=13&amp;source=embed">George’s First Hike</a> in a larger map</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our First Family Day Out]]></title>
    <link href="/george/our-first-family-day-out/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T20:08:02Z</updated>
    <id>/george/our-first-family-day-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8593.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8593-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Over the weekend we decided it was about time we had our first family day out so, after a bit of to-ing and fro-ing about where to go, we decided against the beach and headed up to the Forest of Dean to visit <a href="http://www.puzzlewood.net/">Puzzlewood</a>. The place was described as a “Magical Day Out in the Forest of Dean”, but what grabbed us most about it was the belief that this part of the Forest of Dean was the inspiration for the Forests of Middle Earth (the mythical land imagined by J. R. R. Tolkien in The Lord of the Rings, for those Philistines who don’t know what/where Middle Earth is!).</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8599.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8599-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>On arrival, it didn’t look like much. The car park was a field, there was a disused café on the way to the entrance and it seemed very quiet. However, it really was amazing. Once we were inside the ticket office, we were greeted with an array of cakes, chocolate, assorted souvenirs and some very welcoming staff. We bought our tickets and got back out into the sunshine. On the path into the woods there was a straw bale maze which was seriously cool, although George was rather nonplussed by it.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8612.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8612-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>The Puzzlewood itself was definitely a beautiful place to visit. We entered the wood and it does immediately remind you (or at least it reminded us) of some mythical forest from Middle Earth. Strange rock formations coated in moss litter the entire area, there are barriers made out of the trees protecting visitors from various sink holes and chasms all over the place. We slowly meandered our way around Puzzlewood, taking in all the different sites, but George slept like a baby (obviously) until we were about half way round. Was he thinking it was about time to have a look himself? No. He wanted food, and he wanted it right now! It was nice an quiet where we were so we sloped off down one of the many pathways and settled down on a bench for George to eat.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8686.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8686-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>For a change, George went straight back to sleep once he was fed so Rosie and I carried on regardless and enjoyed the rest of our morning. Whilst having lunch in the garden outside the new café we planned out the rest of our day. Next stop Gloucester Cathedral, a filming location for some corridors in the Harry Potter films including the one where the “The chamber of secrets has been opened, enemies of the heir … beware” message was written on the wall.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8667.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/03/First-Family-Day-Out-8667-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>When we arrived we were greeted by an art exhibition and a full concert rehearsal :-). It was brilliant. Whilst we wandered around the halls, we got a preview of the concert due to be held on Saturday evening. It really gave the cathedral a lively atmosphere. Typically, just as we were leaving, the choir and orchestra were coming to a crescendo and George was sleeping happily in his pram. However, we needn’t have worried as George was completely unphased by the whole thing and continued to enjoy his afternoon nap!</p>

<p>We finished up our first family day out with scones and cream at Gloucester Quays. It was a great day out, but hopefully George will stay awake for more of the next one :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>