<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Perry</title>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Just another blog about nothing</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 08:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 08:27:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
      <item>
        <title>George's Second Year</title>
        <link>/george/second-year/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 18:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/images/second-year/George-Rosies-Birthday-2014-9194.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumbs/second-year/George-Rosies-Birthday-2014-9194.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;George &amp;amp; Rosie&#39;s Birthday&quot; class=&quot;alignleft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;George is now another year older so how has the second year gone? Well, it’s been very different to the first year! Having recovered from his illness over the new year, George got back on his feet and hasn’t really stopped since. Rosie has had to open the eyes in the back of her head to try to keep up with him. Unfortunately, just before his first birthday, we discovered George has nut allergy so that has been interesting, considering we used to cook everything in groundnut oil and peanut butter was our favourite breakfast addition. Nevermind, we have adapted quite well I think and George hasn’t had any problems this year so it’s all good :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the year he has definitely developed his own personality and he has grown up so much! He is yet to start speaking, but he does say a number of words now and can sign sentences (although he doesn’t bother very often). We have had a National Trust membership for the last year so we’ve visited lots of different old houses and gardens giving George plenty of opportunity to run and play outside, and he seems to have loved every minute of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of the key events in his second year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07 February – George completed his first full year in this world&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;26 February – George gets tooth number 9&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01 March – George’s 10th tooth breaks through&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;04 March – George gets his 11th tooth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 March – George learnt to clap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01 – 07 April George’s First Visit Abroad (Paris &amp;amp; Disneyland)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01 June - Hamleys Photoshoot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07 June – George gets 2 new teeth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;08 June – Venture Photography Photoshoot &amp;amp; George escapes his cot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;26 June – Georges Allergy test – waste of time!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 September – George given his first training chopsticks!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;26 November – George reached 50 signs!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;03 December – All George’s teeth are now through!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07 February 2014 – George now weighs 11.7kg and is  82cm tall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we’re looking forward to another great year discovering who our little man is.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2013 Year in Review</title>
        <link>/reviews/2013/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 13:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year all! As seems to be customary for blog writers, I thought I would do a bit of a year in review for 2013, so here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;achievements&quot;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of the year, I officially became a student once again (although I started the course in November last year) as part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leadershipmanagementtraining.org.uk/leadership_for_construction.php&quot;&gt;20Twenty Leadership for Construction&lt;/a&gt; programme run by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.cardiffmet.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;Cardiff Metropolitan University&lt;/a&gt;. I was somehow stitched up with this through work ;-) . The course consisted of numerous 2 day blocks of teaching across the year, three essays and culminated in a Strategic Growth Project. I completed it at the beginning of November with good marks in all my assignments. I have not yet been given the overall final grade, but I have definitely passed so I now have a Postgraduate Certificate in Sustainable Leadership (Construction) :-) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of December 2012, George stopped walking whilst he was ill, but by February there was no stopping him and now he walks, runs, jumps (almost) and climbs on everything. He is great fun. In February, after 5 months of baby signing classes, George signed his first word, ‘food’ :-) . By the summer he was signing a  small number of things, but from the middle of September, he really started to progress quickly and now he can sign 56 words! He is also now saying 8 words clearly :-D . Also,  the last of George’s baby teeth came through in the first week of December so hopefully that’s the end of teething :-) . He’s growing up so quick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, I made a potentially stupid mistake and signed up for my second half marathon, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://royalparkshalf.com/&quot;&gt;Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt; in October. I put in a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/50-days-to-go/&quot;&gt;training&lt;/a&gt; to make sure I could actually achieve it, I even joined a running club in September (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caerleonrunningclub.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Caerleon Running Club&lt;/a&gt;). When the day arrived, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/&quot;&gt;completed the race&lt;/a&gt; and beat my previous time by 17 minutes finishing in a time of 1:48:10 :-D . After joining the running club, I got more involved in the local running community and ran my first &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parkrun.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Parkrun&lt;/a&gt; at the end of November in a time of 22:01. With all the half marathon training and club running I managed to complete 500 miles running in 2013. Maybe I’ll aim for 550 miles this year ;-) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”square” ids=”591,1194,1200”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013 also seemed to be the year for DIY. In May, we finally decided to decorate the walls and beds in the back garden and put up a fence along the side, and across the drive to pen George in during the summer. So, one weekend, with the help of Rosie and my dad, we set out and installed a low close board fence. It was great fun, but we didn’t have enough timber to finish the gate. As such it still isn’t finished :-( . June saw us building a new barbecue next to our garage with some waste materials from work and in August we built a wall at the end of the steps to finish off the top of the patio. Inside the house, we decided to brighten the place up with some vinyl stickers and we’re looking forward to doing some more extensive work this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”square” ids=”1182,1183,1184,1185,1186,1187,1188,1189,1190”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;events&quot;&gt;Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of January we had our traditional Christmas Ham for the Perry Family Christmas which George has managed to see twice already! Then in February George completed his first full revolution of the sun. We had a selection of party’s for family and friends (mainly for us, but George seemed to enjoy himself too ;-) ) as well as for Rosie’s birthday so she didn’t feel left out ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My birthday, once again, coincided with &lt;a href=&quot;http://scouts.org.uk/reunion/&quot;&gt;Gilwell Reunion&lt;/a&gt; so we tacked on an extra day to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.draytonmanor.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Drayton Manor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.draytonmanor.co.uk/thomas-land.php&quot;&gt;Thomas Land&lt;/a&gt;. It was another great birthday, and George loved Thomas Land!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent Easter in France with friends where we visited &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disneylandparis.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Disneyland&lt;/a&gt; and the sights of Paris. It was a brilliant couple of days, but we tried to fit too much in so it was a bit hectic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas this year was a little unusual because both sets of our parents were around on the big day :-D . We started the holiday by visiting Rosie’s Grandparents on the Isle of Wight. We then headed to Basingstoke to visit my sister with my parents and Gran. We had Christmas at home with my parents visiting in the morning, Rosie’s parents arriving in the afternoon and all of them joining us for the evening. It was a brilliant day, and although we’ve all got stinking colds now, we wouldn’t change it for the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”square” ids=”1155,1173,1160,1161,1172,1162,1180,1181,1179,1198,1209,1199,1203,1204,1205,1206,1207,1208”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;days-out&quot;&gt;Days Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Rosie &amp;amp; George recovered from their late 2012 tummy bug, we began the year by taking George for a walk to the top of the Sugar Loaf in the Black Mountains. We were joined by Mark for this great start to the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of January we were able to officially introduce George to snow, and he loved it. We also picked up National Trust memberships to encourage us to go on more days out. It was obviously a good incentive as we have been out and about a lot this year. In August, we got involved with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gromitunleashed.org.uk/&quot;&gt;hunt for Gromit&lt;/a&gt; across Bristol giving us several days out visiting parts of Bristol we may never have gone to otherwise. Here’s a small selection of photos from our adventures :-) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”square” ids=”1154,1156,1157,1212,1168,1170,1171,1211,1213,1214,1215,1216,1217,1218,1219,1220,1222,1223,1224,1225,1226,1227,1228,1237,1229,1230,1231,1232,1233,1234,1235,1236,1238”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;freerunning&quot;&gt;Freerunning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also decided to take up a new hobby early in the year and joined Torfaen Freerunning Academy to learn all about Freerunning &amp;amp; Parkour. The club met weekly at a gym in New Inn so it was great, although they stopped running at the beginning of August. I had a lot of fun with this gymnastic sport, managing to get a handle on the backflip in April :-) . I will continue with the freerunning on my own for now, but I have a feeling my progress will be a little slower until the club restarts or I find another one :-( .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”square” ids=”1240,1241,1242,1221,1243”]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, 2013 wasn’t all good. In February we discovered that George has a nut allergy, not a major allergy, but an allergy all the same meaning he has to miss out on some of the best food around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made the tough decision to leave FreeSpirit ESU (the Explorer Scout Unit where we were leaders) after 10 years. It has been a huge part of our lives for so long, but we felt it was time to move on to spend more time with George.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may not have improved my Chinese at all since the end of my challenge, but I’ve had a good year and I’m looking forward to what 2014 brings :-) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are links to my WordPress Year in Blogging, Facebook Year in Review and Google+ Photo/Video montage of the year. All of these have been provided automatically by each company with the use of my published data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jetpack.me/annual-report/28088045/2013/&quot;&gt;WordPess 2013 Year in Blogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/yearinreview/richardpperry&quot;&gt;Facebook Year in Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5E7CcMLZkao&amp;amp;w=550&amp;amp;rel=0&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instagram Digest Nov-Dec 2013</title>
        <link>/photography/instagram-nov-dec-2013/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>
&lt;div class=&quot;oembed photo&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&#39;http://distilleryimage4.ak.instagram.com/af0770944d7111e3bae212a54e5f236d_8.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;The ingredients list on mango &amp;amp; cinnamon tea, what&#39;s missing??&#39; /&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;oembed photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage5.ak.instagram.com/fc4c3e885f4211e3ae811209a296472f_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;George helping to decorate the Christmas tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;oembed photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage5.ak.instagram.com/0357547c688711e3930b12a8405163f1_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A poi display at the lantern parade on Jersey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;oembed photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage5.ak.instagram.com/11bf36686ef611e3b28012d40f8b39a1_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A well deserved gingerbread latte after a rather successful shopping trip&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instagram Digest Oct 2013</title>
        <link>/photography/instagram-oct-13/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 20:21:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”rectangular” ids=”1110,1107,1079,1074,1071,1066,1063,1060,1056,1053,1049,1044,1041,1038”]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon</title>
        <link>/general/rpf-half/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 19:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/attachment/2013-10-06-08-27-20/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-08.27.20-150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Waiting at the start&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Well I did it! On 06 October 2013 at 10:54 I crossed the line at the end of my second half marathon. This time it was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.royalparkshalf.com&quot;&gt;Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt; through the Royal Parks in London, and wow! It was an absolutely stunning route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Hyde Park early on the Sunday morning to find a good portion of the 16,000 runners already there. The weather was beautiful and I was excited, after all, the route was due to pass the Houses of Parliament, Trafalgar Square and Buckingham Palace, as well as running through Hyde Park, Kensington Gardens, Green Park and St James Park :-D. A warm up was done by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.britmilfit.com/&quot;&gt;British Military Fitness&lt;/a&gt; on the main stage before we were directed into our pens. It was my plan to take it steady due to the issues over the last 4 weeks with almost no training so I hunted down the 1:50 pacers with the intention of running with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_1116” align=”alignright” width=”180”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marathon-photos.com/scripts/event.py?template=MPX2&amp;amp;new_search=1&amp;amp;event=Sports%2FCPUK%2F2013%2FRoyal%20Parks%20Foundation%20Half%20Marathon&amp;amp;match=6051&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/RPAY2262-300x198.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Passing Buckingham Palace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; © marathon-photos.com[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 09:00 the gun went off and it took me 6 minutes to get to the start line before my race could begin. We headed off at a steady pace and, as planned, I stuck with the 1:50 pacers. The route was just as breathtaking as I expected, but what I hadn’t expected was to feel as emotional as I did about it. As I was running through Admiralty Arch onto the Mall, heading for Buckingham Palace, I felt privileged to be able to take part in this event through one of my favourite cities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-11.14.46.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-11.14.46-150x150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scout runners at the finish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was still with the 1:50 pacers as we headed back into Hyde Park and I was feeling quite good. As we approached the half way mark, I realised that I should be able to run this with a negative split, so I slightly increased my pace. This took me ahead of the pacers, but I was feeling comfortable and felt I was quite capable of holding a steady pace. I carried on through the park with very little idea of where I was in the pack, but I was really enjoying the run so I didn’t really care. At the 800m to go marker I stepped up the pace again, gradually increasing until I was sprinting across the line in a time of 1:48:10!! It was done :-D and this time, the training I had managed to do brought me to the end of the race without the need for a stretcher. I actually felt good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met up with some of the other Scout runners after the race and then spent the rest of the day exploring London and playing in the park with George. It was a fantastic day, and the nicest run I have ever been on :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/attachment/screen-shot-2013-10-18-at-20-16-35/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/Screen-Shot-2013-10-18-at-20.16.35-1024x608.png&quot; alt=&quot;RPF Half Route Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instagram Digest Jul-Sep 2013</title>
        <link>/photography/instagram-jul-sep-13/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2013 15:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”rectangular” ids=”1028,1025,1022,1017,1009,1006,1003,992,989,986,982,979”]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RunKeepers 5th Birthday</title>
        <link>/general/runkeepers-5th-birthday/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 07:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It turns out my favourite running tracker has been around for 5 years now. Check out the infographic they have put together to celebrate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/58241497256/runkeeper-5th-birthday&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/6cb7219912b2eaf178d20dd7ca1801c1/tumblr_mrh6xetIK21qzunbuo1_r1_1280.png&quot; alt=&quot;Five years ago this past Sunday, a small crew of very hardworking people pushed a button to send RunKeeper to the iTunes App Store for the first time. Lots has happened in the roughly 1826 days since then, and it’s all because of you! Take a look at all we&amp;#8217;ve accomplished together these last five years.  &quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/57968902569/five-years-ago-today&quot;&gt;http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/57968902569/five-years-ago-today&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>50 days to go!</title>
        <link>/general/50-days-to-go/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/?attachment_id=999&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/08/2013-07-26-20.45.12-225x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In My Scout Running Vest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As I am sure most people that know me are aware, I am running the &lt;a href=&quot;http://royalparkshalf.com&quot;&gt;Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt; to raise money for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scouts.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Scout Association&lt;/a&gt;. Well, there are now only 50 days to go to race day so I thought I would do a bit of a write up to try and drum up some more support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-am-i-running&quot;&gt;Why Am I Running?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an email from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scouts.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Scouts&lt;/a&gt; describing a number of &lt;a href=&quot;http://scouts.org.uk/challengeevents/&quot;&gt;Challenge Events&lt;/a&gt; that were running, and for which they needed volunteers. Well, I quite enjoy running so when I saw the &lt;a href=&quot;http://royalparkshalf.com&quot;&gt;RPF Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt;, I thought why not. Now although that was my first reason for running, the main reason is obviously to raise money to support the Scouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been a Scout at various stages since I was 8 years old, 10 years as a youth member and 10 years as a leader. I’ve had some wonderful opportunities through Scouts over the years, and have seen many young people really develop since becoming a leader. It is an organisation that I am proud to be a part of, and I believe the benefits that the organisation brings to young people are huge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since becoming a Scout I have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trekked across the Central River Division of The Gambia as part of a 3 man team (amongst a much larger team);&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Participated in 3 International Jamborees (EuroJam 2005, Serbian Jamboree 2006 &amp;amp; World Scout Jamboree 2007) where I met people from all corners of the globe;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Woken up under a clear sky in the middle of the Mafikeng Safari Park, South Africa on the 1 January 2007 (the Centenary year of Scouts at the birthplace of Scouting);&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spent time with &lt;a href=&quot;http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/mongolia-day-2/&quot;&gt;Nomads on the Plains of Mongolia&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/an-emperors-army-and-hot-springs/&quot;&gt;Terracotta Army in Xi’an, China&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/the-sites-of-beijing/&quot;&gt;Forbidden City in Beijing, China&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As well as endless nights camping, days hiking, kayaking, climbing and learning all sorts of new skills, that have helped me become who I am today, right here in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is due to the dedication of volunteers across the country that I have had the opportunity to experience what I have, but there is also an awful lot of support needed from Scouts as a whole to make sure everything runs smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-will-the-money-be-used-for&quot;&gt;What will the Money be Used For?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the money raised by myself, and everyone else participating in these challenge events, will be used to support the formation of new groups across the country to give more young people the opportunities that myself, and many others, have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-you-sponsor-me&quot;&gt;How Can You Sponsor Me?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to sponsor me then you can do so by any of the following means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justgiving.com/richardpperry&quot;&gt;http://www.justgiving.com/richardpperry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Text “&lt;strong&gt;SCOU74 £2&lt;/strong&gt;” or “&lt;strong&gt;SCOU74 £5&lt;/strong&gt;” or “&lt;strong&gt;SCOU74 £10&lt;/strong&gt;” etc to &lt;strong&gt;70070&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Or by just giving me money and signing a form if you prefer :-)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those of you that have already kindly sponsored me, thank you very much :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instagram Digest Jun 2013</title>
        <link>/photography/instagram-jun-13/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 18:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”rectangular” ids=”961,958,955,952,949,946,933”]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Instagram Digest May 2013</title>
        <link>/photography/instagram-may-13/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 19:31:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>Richard Perry</author>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=”rectangular” link=”post” ids=”864,867,923,918,915,912”]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    

  </channel>
</rss>