<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: general | ]]></title>
  <link href="//general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T08:27:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[{"name"=>"Richard Perry", "email"=>"richard@perrymail.me.uk", "github"=>"richardp2", "twitter"=>"richard_p2"}]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon]]></title>
    <link href="/general/rpf-half/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-18T19:09:19Z</updated>
    <id>/general/rpf-half</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/attachment/2013-10-06-08-27-20/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-08.27.20-150x150.jpg" alt="Waiting at the start" /></a>Well I did it! On 06 October 2013 at 10:54 I crossed the line at the end of my second half marathon. This time it was the <a href="http://www.royalparkshalf.com">Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon</a> through the Royal Parks in London, and wow! It was an absolutely stunning route.</p>

<p>We arrived at Hyde Park early on the Sunday morning to find a good portion of the 16,000 runners already there. The weather was beautiful and I was excited, after all, the route was due to pass the Houses of Parliament, Trafalgar Square and Buckingham Palace, as well as running through Hyde Park, Kensington Gardens, Green Park and St James Park :-D. A warm up was done by <a href="http://www.britmilfit.com/">British Military Fitness</a> on the main stage before we were directed into our pens. It was my plan to take it steady due to the issues over the last 4 weeks with almost no training so I hunted down the 1:50 pacers with the intention of running with them.</p>

<p>[caption id=”attachment_1116” align=”alignright” width=”180”]<a href="http://www.marathon-photos.com/scripts/event.py?template=MPX2&amp;new_search=1&amp;event=Sports%2FCPUK%2F2013%2FRoyal%20Parks%20Foundation%20Half%20Marathon&amp;match=6051"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/RPAY2262-300x198.jpeg" alt="Passing Buckingham Palace" /></a> © marathon-photos.com[/caption]</p>

<p>At 09:00 the gun went off and it took me 6 minutes to get to the start line before my race could begin. We headed off at a steady pace and, as planned, I stuck with the 1:50 pacers. The route was just as breathtaking as I expected, but what I hadn’t expected was to feel as emotional as I did about it. As I was running through Admiralty Arch onto the Mall, heading for Buckingham Palace, I felt privileged to be able to take part in this event through one of my favourite cities!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-11.14.46.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/2013-10-06-11.14.46-150x150.jpg" alt="Scout runners at the finish" /></a>I was still with the 1:50 pacers as we headed back into Hyde Park and I was feeling quite good. As we approached the half way mark, I realised that I should be able to run this with a negative split, so I slightly increased my pace. This took me ahead of the pacers, but I was feeling comfortable and felt I was quite capable of holding a steady pace. I carried on through the park with very little idea of where I was in the pack, but I was really enjoying the run so I didn’t really care. At the 800m to go marker I stepped up the pace again, gradually increasing until I was sprinting across the line in a time of 1:48:10!! It was done :-D and this time, the training I had managed to do brought me to the end of the race without the need for a stretcher. I actually felt good!</p>

<p>We met up with some of the other Scout runners after the race and then spent the rest of the day exploring London and playing in the park with George. It was a fantastic day, and the nicest run I have ever been on :-).</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/attachment/screen-shot-2013-10-18-at-20-16-35/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/10/Screen-Shot-2013-10-18-at-20.16.35-1024x608.png" alt="RPF Half Route Map" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RunKeepers 5th Birthday]]></title>
    <link href="/general/runkeepers-5th-birthday/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T07:03:56Z</updated>
    <id>/general/runkeepers-5th-birthday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It turns out my favourite running tracker has been around for 5 years now. Check out the infographic they have put together to celebrate</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/58241497256/runkeeper-5th-birthday"><img src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/6cb7219912b2eaf178d20dd7ca1801c1/tumblr_mrh6xetIK21qzunbuo1_r1_1280.png" alt="Five years ago this past Sunday, a small crew of very hardworking people pushed a button to send RunKeeper to the iTunes App Store for the first time. Lots has happened in the roughly 1826 days since then, and it’s all because of you! Take a look at all we&#8217;ve accomplished together these last five years.  " /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/57968902569/five-years-ago-today">http://blog.runkeeper.com/post/57968902569/five-years-ago-today</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[50 days to go!]]></title>
    <link href="/general/50-days-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-16T08:00:41Z</updated>
    <id>/general/50-days-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/?attachment_id=999"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/08/2013-07-26-20.45.12-225x300.jpg" alt="In My Scout Running Vest" /></a>As I am sure most people that know me are aware, I am running the <a href="http://royalparkshalf.com">Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon</a> to raise money for the <a href="http://scouts.org.uk/">Scout Association</a>. Well, there are now only 50 days to go to race day so I thought I would do a bit of a write up to try and drum up some more support.</p>

<h3 id="why-am-i-running">Why Am I Running?</h3>

<p>I got an email from the <a href="http://scouts.org.uk/">Scouts</a> describing a number of <a href="http://scouts.org.uk/challengeevents/">Challenge Events</a> that were running, and for which they needed volunteers. Well, I quite enjoy running so when I saw the <a href="http://royalparkshalf.com">RPF Half Marathon</a>, I thought why not. Now although that was my first reason for running, the main reason is obviously to raise money to support the Scouts.</p>

<p>I have been a Scout at various stages since I was 8 years old, 10 years as a youth member and 10 years as a leader. I’ve had some wonderful opportunities through Scouts over the years, and have seen many young people really develop since becoming a leader. It is an organisation that I am proud to be a part of, and I believe the benefits that the organisation brings to young people are huge.</p>

<p>Since becoming a Scout I have:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Trekked across the Central River Division of The Gambia as part of a 3 man team (amongst a much larger team);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Participated in 3 International Jamborees (EuroJam 2005, Serbian Jamboree 2006 &amp; World Scout Jamboree 2007) where I met people from all corners of the globe;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Woken up under a clear sky in the middle of the Mafikeng Safari Park, South Africa on the 1 January 2007 (the Centenary year of Scouts at the birthplace of Scouting);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Spent time with <a href="http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/mongolia-day-2/">Nomads on the Plains of Mongolia</a>;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Visited the <a href="http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/an-emperors-army-and-hot-springs/">Terracotta Army in Xi’an, China</a> and the <a href="http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/scouts/threenations09/the-sites-of-beijing/">Forbidden City in Beijing, China</a>;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>As well as endless nights camping, days hiking, kayaking, climbing and learning all sorts of new skills, that have helped me become who I am today, right here in the UK.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>It is due to the dedication of volunteers across the country that I have had the opportunity to experience what I have, but there is also an awful lot of support needed from Scouts as a whole to make sure everything runs smoothly.</p>

<h3 id="what-will-the-money-be-used-for">What will the Money be Used For?</h3>

<p>All the money raised by myself, and everyone else participating in these challenge events, will be used to support the formation of new groups across the country to give more young people the opportunities that myself, and many others, have had.</p>

<h3 id="how-can-you-sponsor-me">How Can You Sponsor Me?</h3>

<p>If you would like to sponsor me then you can do so by any of the following means:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Visit <a href="http://www.justgiving.com/richardpperry">http://www.justgiving.com/richardpperry</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Text “<strong>SCOU74 £2</strong>” or “<strong>SCOU74 £5</strong>” or “<strong>SCOU74 £10</strong>” etc to <strong>70070</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Or by just giving me money and signing a form if you prefer :-)</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>And for those of you that have already kindly sponsored me, thank you very much :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adobe CS2 available free (sort of)]]></title>
    <link href="/general/adobe-cs2-free/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T19:17:39Z</updated>
    <id>/general/adobe-cs2-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/adobe-cs2-free/attachment/4725429817_c358369edc1/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2013/01/4725429817_c358369edc1-150x150.jpg" alt="Adobe CS2" /></a>Earlier this month, Adobe published a <a href="http://www.adobe.com/downloads/cs2_downloads/index.html">list</a> of download links and serial numbers for their Creative Suite 2 software including Photoshop, Illustrator, Acrobat &amp; others. Suddenly the internet was awash with speculations that Adobe had in fact released Adobe CS2 for free. This is not quite how it was meant to happen though. What actually happened is this:</p>

<p>In December 2012, Adobe turned off their activation servers for CS2 because the software has been around since 2005 and doesn’t play nicely with the latest versions of Windows and Mac OS X. A number of CS2 users then encountered problems when reinstalling the software for whatever reason and so there were complaints made to Adobe. In response to this, they published a list of serial numbers and links to download the software that did not require activation. This was originally only available with an Adobe account.</p>

<p>When people started advertising the ‘free’ software, Adobe piped up and stated that the software was only for people that have previously bought CS2 and were having problems with activation. However, this was not published on the <a href="http://www.adobe.com/downloads/cs2_downloads/index.html">download page</a> and worse still, they have now taken off the requirement to log into their site to download the software. So, for all intents and purposes, Adobe CS2 is now available free of charge.</p>

<p>A number of people across the internet have now read through the EULA included with the downloaded software and found that as long as you download the software from their webpage and use the license keys supplied it is completely legal to install and use CS2 free of charge. Please note, however, that Adobe don’t ‘officially’ agree with this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Awesome Birthday Weekend]]></title>
    <link href="/general/birthday-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-18T20:00:35Z</updated>
    <id>/general/birthday-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-4/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1087-150x150.jpg" alt="Entrance to the ExCeL Arena" /></a>This year, my birthday landed on Gilwell Reunion weekend so Rosie decided to put together an amazing weekend based at Gilwell Park. Gilwell Reunion is a weekend for Scout Leaders that doesn’t involve bringing along any Scouts so it’s a brilliant chill out weekend where we get to catch up with friends from all over the world that we’ve met on various events, so it’s always nice when it lands on my birthday. This year, Rosie also arranged for us to take a trip into London on Saturday to watch some wheelchair fencing at the ExCeL Centre.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-2/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1056-150x150.jpg" alt="Me &amp; George Outside the North Greenwich Arena" /></a>We arrived late on the Friday night for various reasons, and headed out early on Saturday morning to get into London, so we didn’t really take part in Friday night or Saturday at Reunion, but the Paralympic Games more than made up for this. Our session was due to start at 11:00 at the ExCeL Centre so we took a scenic route to get there. We got the tube through to the <del>O2</del> North Greenwich Arena so that we could take the Emirates Air Line across to ExCeL. Thankfully the weather was great so we could see for miles all the way across east London. The views were incredible, and if you haven’t already had a chance to go on it, then you really should. It only lasts for a bit more than 5 minutes, but it’s well worth it! We arrived at the ExCeL with plenty of time to spare so I took the opportunity to give Rosie &amp; George the tour of the place I spent the two weeks of the Olympics (although I couldn’t get everywhere because, apparently, my accreditation was only valid for the Olympics!). <a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-3/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1106-150x150.jpg" alt="Hong Kong Smashing Great Britain in Wheelchair Fencing" /></a>We also realised that the tickets we had were day passes so we were able to watch anything that had spare seats :-). As our tickets were for the wheelchair fencing first &amp; foremost, that was where we began our day. The quarter finals of the men’s team event was on, and GBR were fighting Hong Kong. It seems that Hong Kong are ridiculously good in comparison to GBR, so we watched our guys getting knocked out (45 - 19). The way the competitors moved, bearing in mind their wheelchairs were locked in place, was pretty incredible. I enjoyed the Olympic Fencing, but the Paralympic fencing was far more exciting and appeared a lot more difficult. One thing I wasn’t expecting though, was some of the competitors being able to walk!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-5/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1173-150x150.jpg" alt="Wheelchair Table Tennis" /></a>The next stop was the Table Tennis. We had no idea what category/stage was taking place, so it was quite good to find it was the Category 4-5 (wheelchair) team medal matches. Again, the wheelchairs were not even a slight hindrance to these guys, they were bouncing the chairs left and right to reach the ball as if it was the most natural thing in the world. The entire thing seemed effortless to them. The games were also just as fast paced as the Olympic table tennis, which I (ashamedly) didn’t expect because of the perceived difficulty moving back and forth along the table edge. The whole thing was a real eye opener for me. Olympians are always praised for the effort and skill involved in reaching the peak of their discipline, but Paralympians never seem to get the same recognition. In my humble opinion, the Paralympians deserve to be recognised in exactly the same way because they show the world that the word ‘disabled’ is simply a matter of mind. They are all less able, in one way or another, than somebody else, but their so-called ‘disabilities’ do not stop them from living their life the same as everyone else. It seems to me that ‘disabled’ is a moniker that can only really be applied to those that have given up, or believe that their disability defines them.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-6/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1214-150x150.jpg" alt="The three of us with Wenlock &amp; Mandeville" /></a>Before heading back to Gilwell Reunion, we decided to check out the view over the Olympic Park from the viewing gallery at John Lewis at the Westfield Centre. This was perhaps one of our less well-considered ideas. We had to fight against the hoards of people thronging through the shopping centre before joining the queue to get to the viewing gallery. When we finally got there, the view was less than fantastic. I can’t argue against the description, it was actually a view of the whole park, but it wasn’t looking down over the park so it was very difficult to actually see anything. Nevermind, the money was for charity so it doesn’t matter really.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-7/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1237-150x150.jpg" alt="Georges First Gilwell Reunion Campfire" /></a>We got back to site in time to have a quick dinner of fish &amp; chips before wandering over to the Gilwell Camp Fire. It wasn’t George’s first campfire, but it was his first Gilwell Reunion campfire and they do things a little differently here. Unfortunately, he was so tired from the day that he didn’t really enjoy it and so Rosie &amp; I spent some time trying to get him to settle away from it all. We had to take him straight to bed when we got back to the tent and so decided to retire ourselves.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-8/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1248-150x150.jpg" alt="George with the UKCC Wayne Bulpitt" /></a>The next day we were able to take part in Gilwell Reunion, so we strolled around the various stalls around the site and caught up with friends from all over the place. George even got to meet Wayne Bulpitt. I do enjoy Gilwell, even if it is a little overpriced. This year we were even able to stay for the AGM and have a nice chilled out day because we were planning on staying in London another night. We stayed in Chingford to have dinner with Mark before heading to the hotel closer to Watford, but just as we were leaving site we got a phone call from the hotel telling us that our booking had been transferred due to an incident at the hotel. Lucky we hadn’t already left then really! We reprogrammed our sat nav and found our way to the other hotel with no problems.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-9/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1266-150x150.jpg" alt="Warner Bros. Studio Tour Entrance" /></a>The last part of my birthday weekend was a visit to the <a href="http://www.wbstudiotour.co.uk/">Warner Bros. Studio Tour London - The Making of Harry Potter</a> so, after our usual leisurely breakfast, we checked out of the hotel and made our way to the studios ready for our preallocated entrance time of 10:30. Unfortunately we arrived at the same time as a bus full of school kids! This seemed like an ideal time to make sure George had a clean nappy and wasn’t hungry.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-10/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1283-150x150.jpg" alt="The Cupboard Under the Stairs" /></a>The tour began with a the obligatory queue when we got to see the Cupboard Under the Stairs and Rosie managed to get me a birthday badge. We were ushered into a small room that had videos on each wall introducing how Harry Potter was chosen to become the next franchise, and then into an auditorium. This was where the tour really began, with an introduction to the Studio Tour by one of the staff, and then by Daniel Radcliffe, Rupert Grint and Emma Watson (on video of course). Once this finished the screen lifted up to reveal the actual doors to the Great Hall! What a brilliant way to open!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-11/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1289-150x150.jpg" alt="Rosie &amp; George at the Entrance to the Great Hall" /></a>For the next few hours, we walked around Studio J (the home of the various sets, props costumes etc) taking in the enormity of the task to create the world of Harry Potter, ably guided by Tom Felton aka Dracy Malfoy via an audio/video guide (basically an iPod Touch in a custom case with a custom app running on it). We got to see the table decorations from the Yule Ball, the Mirror of Erised, the Goblet of Fire, the Triwizard Cup, the trunk that held Alastor Moody, the vanishing cabinet, the Death Eater masks, thousands of wands, junk from the Room of Requirement, the horcruxes, the portraits, the Great Hall, Dumbledores Office, the Gryffindor Common Room &amp; bedroom, Hagrids Hut, the Burrow kitchen and so much more. I was like a kid in a candy shop! It really was brilliant to see how, and to what level of detail, it was all built.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-12/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/09/Birthday-Weekend-1487-150x150.jpg" alt="Rosie on the Knight Bus" /></a>After leaving Studio J, we moved out to the back lot where we got to try Butterbeer (not entirely convinced on this one, probably an acquired taste) and had lunch. The back lot is where a lot of the bigger props and sets are located including the Knight Bus (yes that’s right, it really exists and wasn’t just done with CGI), Sirius Blacks motorbike, the Ford Anglia, Tom Riddles gravestone, 4 Privet Drive, the Potter house from Godric’s Hollow, the bridge and the full size wizards chess pieces. This was brilliant, but the fact that you could actually get one the Knight Bus, Sirius Blacks motorbike and the Ford Anglia just made it that much better. Also, they’ve recently opened up the bridge to visitors so we got to cross that as well!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-14/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1518-150x150.jpg" alt="Goblin Heads in Creature Effects" /></a>I really was having an amazing day at this point, and we still had the creature workshop and the models to go :-). Just as the rain started coming down we moved on to Studio K. On entering the first room of the creature workshop, we were confronted by shelf upon shelf of goblin heads. This led on to a number of workbenches with various prosthetics and models on display in various states of completeness. This was also where we came across an animatronic Hagrid! It turns out that for some of the scenes it was necessary to use this model because of how big Hagrid is meant to be. In the centre of the room, they also had a display of a Fawkes, Mandrake, Hedwig &amp; dying Voldemort models that were hooked up to buttons so you could see them working.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-15/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1545-150x150.jpg" alt="Buckbeak" /></a>The main creature effects workshop area then leads into an area displaying some of the larger creatures including the Basilisk (both the living one and the skeleton), a Thestral, a dragon, Buckbeak and Aragog, and they really were big!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-16/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1554-150x150.jpg" alt="Diagon Alley" /></a>We then found ourselves in the real Diagon Alley set, complete with Ollivanders, Eyelops, Flourish &amp; Blotts, Weasleys’ Wizard Wheezes and Gringotts to name a few. This was the actual set used for all the films where Diagon Alley appeared, and if it wasn’t for the walkway that had been installed in the centre, this would have been a ‘hot’ set (i.e. ready for filming), which I thought was pretty cool. There was even a moving broomstick in the window of Quality Quidditch Supplies.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-17/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1574-150x150.jpg" alt="The Art Department" /></a>At this point I thought we were nearing the end with only the main Hogwarts model to go. How wrong could I be! We still had the art department to visit. This was one of the most amazing parts of the tour for me because it really gave an idea of how difficult it is to actually build a realistic looking set, and what steps need to be taken before any actual construction takes place. It seemed to me that it would be more difficult to build a realistic looking set for a film like Harry Potter than to build a landmark building in the real world!</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-18/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1606-150x150.jpg" alt="The Burrow Model" /></a>In this section there were endless technical drawings plastered over the high walls (reminiscent of my last site office at BAM) with shelves full of box files, and architectural models of absolutely everything. Not only was all this stuff on display for the public, but nobody had any issues with you taking pictures of whatever you liked. There were also various different artists impressions of sets, characters and scenes on display along the walls of one of the corridors, and these were absolutely stunning! Unfortunately, very few of them were available to buy.</p>

<p><a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/birthday-weekend/attachment/birthday-weekend-20/"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/10/Birthday-Weekend-1634-150x150.jpg" alt="1:24 Scale Model of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft &amp; Wizardry" /></a> Then came the pièce de résistance, the 1:24 scale model of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft &amp; Wizardry  It was, in a word, breathtaking. The sheer scale of the thing was incredible! The room that housed the model was set up with a descending ramp that wrapped all the way around the model so you could get the full impression of the structure. They had programmed the lighting to cycle through day and night on a fairly regular basis as well, so you could see the building in all its glory at various times of artificial day. Around the edges were interactive info panels that showed how they used the model when filming the exterior scenes for the movie. There were fly throughs that started in the model, then transitioned through to the post processed imagery giving a really good impression of how it all worked.</p>

<p>Well after an impressive 5½ hours, we were done and visiting the gift shop. I can’t quite believe we were in there for that long, especially given that neither of us felt that it had dragged, or was taking too long. I think I could have spent more time in Studio J, but otherwise I think it was just right. We had a brilliant time and I would thoroughly recommend it to anyone who is into Harry Potter or has aspirations to get into film making/set building etc.</p>

<p>Thank you Rosie for a fantastic weekend!</p>

<p><a href="http://photos.perry-online.me.uk/events/2012/birthday-weekend/">More Photos - 0907 - 0910 Richards Birthday Weekend</a></p>

<p><a href="http://photos.perry-online.me.uk/events/2012/birthday-weekend/making-of-harry-potter">More Photos - Warner Bros. Studio Tour London - The Making of Harry Potter</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>