<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reviews | ]]></title>
  <link href="//reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T08:27:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[{"name"=>"Richard Perry", "email"=>"richard@perrymail.me.uk", "github"=>"richardp2", "twitter"=>"richard_p2"}]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 Year in Review]]></title>
    <link href="/reviews/2013/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-03T13:23:11Z</updated>
    <id>/reviews/2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy New Year all! As seems to be customary for blog writers, I thought I would do a bit of a year in review for 2013, so here it is.</p>

<h3 id="achievements">Achievements</h3>

<p>At the start of the year, I officially became a student once again (although I started the course in November last year) as part of the <a href="http://www.leadershipmanagementtraining.org.uk/leadership_for_construction.php">20Twenty Leadership for Construction</a> programme run by <a href="http://www3.cardiffmet.ac.uk/">Cardiff Metropolitan University</a>. I was somehow stitched up with this through work ;-) . The course consisted of numerous 2 day blocks of teaching across the year, three essays and culminated in a Strategic Growth Project. I completed it at the beginning of November with good marks in all my assignments. I have not yet been given the overall final grade, but I have definitely passed so I now have a Postgraduate Certificate in Sustainable Leadership (Construction) :-) .</p>

<p>At the end of December 2012, George stopped walking whilst he was ill, but by February there was no stopping him and now he walks, runs, jumps (almost) and climbs on everything. He is great fun. In February, after 5 months of baby signing classes, George signed his first word, ‘food’ :-) . By the summer he was signing a  small number of things, but from the middle of September, he really started to progress quickly and now he can sign 56 words! He is also now saying 8 words clearly :-D . Also,  the last of George’s baby teeth came through in the first week of December so hopefully that’s the end of teething :-) . He’s growing up so quick!</p>

<p>In April, I made a potentially stupid mistake and signed up for my second half marathon, the <a href="http://royalparkshalf.com/">Royal Parks Foundation Half Marathon</a> in October. I put in a lot of <a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/50-days-to-go/">training</a> to make sure I could actually achieve it, I even joined a running club in September (<a href="http://www.caerleonrunningclub.co.uk/">Caerleon Running Club</a>). When the day arrived, I <a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/general/rpf-half/">completed the race</a> and beat my previous time by 17 minutes finishing in a time of 1:48:10 :-D . After joining the running club, I got more involved in the local running community and ran my first <a href="http://www.parkrun.org.uk/">Parkrun</a> at the end of November in a time of 22:01. With all the half marathon training and club running I managed to complete 500 miles running in 2013. Maybe I’ll aim for 550 miles this year ;-) .</p>

<p>[gallery type=”square” ids=”591,1194,1200”]</p>

<p>2013 also seemed to be the year for DIY. In May, we finally decided to decorate the walls and beds in the back garden and put up a fence along the side, and across the drive to pen George in during the summer. So, one weekend, with the help of Rosie and my dad, we set out and installed a low close board fence. It was great fun, but we didn’t have enough timber to finish the gate. As such it still isn’t finished :-( . June saw us building a new barbecue next to our garage with some waste materials from work and in August we built a wall at the end of the steps to finish off the top of the patio. Inside the house, we decided to brighten the place up with some vinyl stickers and we’re looking forward to doing some more extensive work this year.</p>

<p>[gallery type=”square” ids=”1182,1183,1184,1185,1186,1187,1188,1189,1190”]</p>

<h3 id="events">Events</h3>

<p>At the end of January we had our traditional Christmas Ham for the Perry Family Christmas which George has managed to see twice already! Then in February George completed his first full revolution of the sun. We had a selection of party’s for family and friends (mainly for us, but George seemed to enjoy himself too ;-) ) as well as for Rosie’s birthday so she didn’t feel left out ;-)</p>

<p>My birthday, once again, coincided with <a href="http://scouts.org.uk/reunion/">Gilwell Reunion</a> so we tacked on an extra day to visit <a href="http://www.draytonmanor.co.uk/">Drayton Manor</a> and <a href="http://www.draytonmanor.co.uk/thomas-land.php">Thomas Land</a>. It was another great birthday, and George loved Thomas Land!</p>

<p>We spent Easter in France with friends where we visited <a href="http://www.disneylandparis.co.uk/">Disneyland</a> and the sights of Paris. It was a brilliant couple of days, but we tried to fit too much in so it was a bit hectic.</p>

<p>Christmas this year was a little unusual because both sets of our parents were around on the big day :-D . We started the holiday by visiting Rosie’s Grandparents on the Isle of Wight. We then headed to Basingstoke to visit my sister with my parents and Gran. We had Christmas at home with my parents visiting in the morning, Rosie’s parents arriving in the afternoon and all of them joining us for the evening. It was a brilliant day, and although we’ve all got stinking colds now, we wouldn’t change it for the world!</p>

<p>[gallery type=”square” ids=”1155,1173,1160,1161,1172,1162,1180,1181,1179,1198,1209,1199,1203,1204,1205,1206,1207,1208”]</p>

<h3 id="days-out">Days Out</h3>

<p>After Rosie &amp; George recovered from their late 2012 tummy bug, we began the year by taking George for a walk to the top of the Sugar Loaf in the Black Mountains. We were joined by Mark for this great start to the year.</p>

<p>At the end of January we were able to officially introduce George to snow, and he loved it. We also picked up National Trust memberships to encourage us to go on more days out. It was obviously a good incentive as we have been out and about a lot this year. In August, we got involved with the <a href="http://www.gromitunleashed.org.uk/">hunt for Gromit</a> across Bristol giving us several days out visiting parts of Bristol we may never have gone to otherwise. Here’s a small selection of photos from our adventures :-) .</p>

<p>[gallery type=”square” ids=”1154,1156,1157,1212,1168,1170,1171,1211,1213,1214,1215,1216,1217,1218,1219,1220,1222,1223,1224,1225,1226,1227,1228,1237,1229,1230,1231,1232,1233,1234,1235,1236,1238”]</p>

<h3 id="freerunning">Freerunning</h3>

<p>I also decided to take up a new hobby early in the year and joined Torfaen Freerunning Academy to learn all about Freerunning &amp; Parkour. The club met weekly at a gym in New Inn so it was great, although they stopped running at the beginning of August. I had a lot of fun with this gymnastic sport, managing to get a handle on the backflip in April :-) . I will continue with the freerunning on my own for now, but I have a feeling my progress will be a little slower until the club restarts or I find another one :-( .</p>

<p>[gallery type=”square” ids=”1240,1241,1242,1221,1243”]</p>

<p>However, 2013 wasn’t all good. In February we discovered that George has a nut allergy, not a major allergy, but an allergy all the same meaning he has to miss out on some of the best food around!</p>

<p>We also made the tough decision to leave FreeSpirit ESU (the Explorer Scout Unit where we were leaders) after 10 years. It has been a huge part of our lives for so long, but we felt it was time to move on to spend more time with George.</p>

<p>I may not have improved my Chinese at all since the end of my challenge, but I’ve had a good year and I’m looking forward to what 2014 brings :-) .</p>

<p>Below are links to my WordPress Year in Blogging, Facebook Year in Review and Google+ Photo/Video montage of the year. All of these have been provided automatically by each company with the use of my published data.</p>

<p><a href="http://jetpack.me/annual-report/28088045/2013/">WordPess 2013 Year in Blogging</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/yearinreview/richardpperry">Facebook Year in Review</a></p>

<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5E7CcMLZkao&amp;w=550&amp;rel=0</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 8 Consumer Preview]]></title>
    <link href="/reviews/windows-8-consumer-preview/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T18:47:07Z</updated>
    <id>/reviews/windows-8-consumer-preview</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of last month Microsoft released their Consumer Preview for Windows 8 and, as usual, I couldn’t resist the temptation, so I promptly downloaded the ISO to have a play :-). Now I think it’s about time I shared my experience with you.</p>

<h3 id="installation">Installation</h3>

<p>As you would expect with a new release of Windows, the installation process is once again very simple.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Insert the CD into the drive and boot the computer</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Select your language, time &amp; currency, and your keyboard layout</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Click Install Now</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter your product code and agree to the Terms &amp; Conditions</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Select install type (Upgrade or Custom/Clean install)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Choose where to install</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Once Windows has completed the installation steps, you are then guided through the initial Out of Box Experience (OOBE), otherwise known as the initial setup and personalisation of the system. This is where you are first introduced to the new Metro UI. Each option screen takes up the whole screen with no borders or menu bars etc. Finally, instead of asking you to setup a user account on the computer, you are now presented with a screen asking you to sign into you Microsoft account (previously known as a Windows Live ID). This isn’t compulsory, there is an option to sign in without a Microsoft account at the bottom of the screen.</p>

<p>That’s it. Now the computer loads up into the new operating system ready to go.</p>

<h3 id="first-impressions">First Impressions</h3>

<p><a href="/images//start_screen.jpg"><img src="/images/thumbs//start_screen.jpg" alt="Windows 8 Start Screen" /></a>Once Windows 8 is installed, you are presented with the brand new Metro Start Button interface. This looks very much like the current Windows Phone  interface, but scrolls horizontally not vertically. This is the replacement for what we currently know as the start button. This shows that Microsoft are now seriously looking at the tablet market. The new interface is very much a new take on many of the popular tablet interfaces currently on the market. I’m not too sure how successful this will be in a desktop environment, but that is what I intend to find out, mainly due to me being devoid of any form of tablet PC at my disposal.</p>

<p><a href="/images//desktop.jpg"><img src="/images/thumbs//desktop.jpg" alt="Windows 8 Desktop" /></a>The first thing that strikes you is that the desktop is not loaded by default, although there is an item in the new Start Menu for the desktop. The default view is the horizontal Start Menu. The ‘tiles’ are neatly arranged in groups and you can move and resize these to suit yourself by simply right clicking the tile you want to change and selecting the relevant option from the popup menu at the bottom of the screen.</p>

<p><a href="/images//start_button.jpg"><img src="/images/thumbs//start_button.jpg" alt="Windows 8 Start Tip" /></a>To make the new UI function on a desktop, as well as a Tablet PC, Windows 8 makes use of ‘Hot Corners’ for accessing the various menus normally accessed by a swipe from the side. Holding the mouse into the lower left corner of the screen brings up the new ‘Start Tip’ (what most people will think of as the new start button) so you can get back to the Start Menu screen from within other applications, or from the desktop. The upper left corner of the screen brings up the switcher showing the previous app in use, but moving the mouse down along the side of the screen brings up other apps. Both right hand corners bring out the new ‘Charms’ menu which gives you access to a number of system tools that are accessible where ever you are in the new Windows 8 ecosystem. Most of these mouse over actions are easy to used to and work very well, but I think I will prefer using WIN+TAB to get the switcher up. That particular bit is a real pain to get right and it seems to disappear before I get the chance to click what I want. I’m sure this is much easier with a tablet, and that it is simply something I will need to get used to when I eventually upgrade properly.</p>

<p>In general I think Windows 8 is going to be another leap forward for Windows, and it all seems very highly polished, but I’m not too sure how your average desktop/laptop user will fair with it as it is clearly designed to be best used on a Tablet PC. I am going to keep using Windows 8 for a little while now to see how it fairs on a laptop, and maybe I’ll do another post about how I fair with it in a few weeks.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>