<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: languages | ]]></title>
  <link href="//languages/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T08:27:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[{"name"=>"Richard Perry", "email"=>"richard@perrymail.me.uk", "github"=>"richardp2", "twitter"=>"richard_p2"}]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandarin Progress Month 4]]></title>
    <link href="/languages/mandarin-month-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-13T15:25:33Z</updated>
    <id>/languages/mandarin-month-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So my 4 months are up and unfortunately, the last 2 months have been a bit useless for various reasons, so needless to say I haven’t really managed to achieve my goal. Over the last month I have probably only spent about 10 hours learning Mandarin, and the bulk of that was probably reviewing characters on <a href="http://www.memrise.com">Memrise</a>. I have still not yet completed all 30 lessons from <a href="http://www.pimsleur.com/Learn-Mandarin-Chinese">Pimsleurs</a> Mandarin 1 so that is still on my todo list.</p>

<p>I have improved by reading comprehension and my speaking a little, but I don’t think I would be able to hold a 5 minute conversation yet. Ah well. I have enjoyed it and so I will continue to plod on at my previous pace and see how it goes. Even though I haven’t achieved what I set out to, I still think it was a worthwhile experiment and I will continue to set targets for future learning in the hope that some day I do manage to learn Mandarin to a conversational level. With that in mind, here are my goals for 2013:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Finish <a href="http://www.pimsleur.com/Learn-Mandarin-Chinese">Pimsleurs</a> Mandarin 1 (yes it’s still here, I’ve got to do it someday!);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Increase my character knowledge to 1,500 characters;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Make use of <a href="http://www.verbling.com/">Verbling</a> (a new service for having short conversations with native speakers) to improve my spoken Mandarin.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>So nothing over the top, but hopefully they’re achievable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandarin Progress Month 3]]></title>
    <link href="/languages/mandarin/mandarin-month-3/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T20:00:26Z</updated>
    <id>/languages/mandarin/mandarin-month-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has now been 3 months since I started my Mandarin Language Challenge so it’s time for another update. This month has been very slow going and I have achieved pretty much nothing. I started the month with the intention of reviewing all the Pimsleur lesson I had learned so far and reciting the conversations from each lesson as SoundCloud items. However, it wasn’t until 15 November that I uploaded the first two lessons, and then I haven’t continued since. I have therefore decided to pretend that November didn’t happen and try to continue from where I left off at the end of October with the same goals etc. carrying forward to December.</p>

<p>For those that are interested, here is the only audio clip I have uploaded in the last month:</p>

<h3 id="pimsleur-mandarin-chinese-i---units-1--2-conversations">Pimsleur Mandarin Chinese I - Units 1 &amp; 2 Conversations</h3>

<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/67516736&amp;color=0066cc&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_artwork=true"></iframe>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandarin Progress Month 2]]></title>
    <link href="/languages/mandarin-month-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T20:31:15Z</updated>
    <id>/languages/mandarin-month-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are now into the third month of my Mandarin Chinese language challenge, so here is an update to how month 2 has gone. Lets start by updating you on my targets from last month.</p>

<h3 id="practice-more-than-twice-a-week">1. Practice more than twice a week</h3>

<p>This time I think I just about managed to practice more than twice a week, although still not as much as I would have liked.</p>

<h3 id="publish-at-least-one-journal-entry-tolang-8httplang-8comper-week">2. Publish at least one journal entry to <a href="http://lang-8.com/">Lang-8</a> per week</h3>

<p>The Lang-8 community are very helpful and I have been inundated with corrections when I have actually submitted an entry, but I did not manage to achieve the requisite on entry per week this month, maybe I will manage it next month. These are my entries for October for anyone that is interested.</p>

<h4 id="week-1---about-mehttplang-8com280403journals171081125e5258525b325e425ba258e25e625882591"><a href="http://lang-8.com/280403/journals/1710811/%25E5%2585%25B3%25E4%25BA%258E%25E6%2588%2591">Week 1 - 关于我 / About Me</a></h4>

<p>我住在一个小城镇叫Pontypool。它是在威尔士南部。
我住跟我的太太和儿子一起。我的儿子是八个月大。
我是一个童军领袖。 我享受攀岩，皮划艇和步行。</p>

<p>I live in a small town called Pontypool. It is in South Wales.
I live with my wife and son. My son is eight months old.
I am a Scout Leader. I enjoy climbing, kayaking and walking.</p>

<h4 id="week-3----family-day-outhttplang-8com280403journals174066225e525ae25b625e525ba25ad25e7259a258425e425b8258025e525a425a9"><a href="http://lang-8.com/280403/journals/1740662/%25E5%25AE%25B6%25E5%25BA%25AD%25E7%259A%2584%25E4%25B8%2580%25E5%25A4%25A9">Week 3 - 家庭的一天 / Family Day Out</a></h4>

<p>昨天我的太太，我的儿子和我去看看在 Bristol 动物园的 恐龙。我们也看看企鹅，灰沼狸和猴。我们有一个非常愉快的一天，George 也有乐趣。我们吃晚饭在McDonald’s。</p>

<p>Yesterday my wife, my son and I went to Bristol Zoo to see the dinosaurs. We also saw the penguins, meerkats &amp; monkeys. We had a very nice day and George had fun too. We had dinner at McDonald’s.</p>

<p>And I’m afraid that’s it for this month!</p>

<h3 id="publish-at-least-two-audio-clips-tosoundcloudhttpsoundcloudcom">3. Publish at least two audio clips to <a href="http://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a></h3>

<p>So I planned to record at least two audio clips to put up on Soundcloud during October, and it was very touch and go, but I just about managed it. The first clip was a basic introduction/about me discussion that was scripted (and corrected via <a href="http://lang-8.com/">Lang-8</a>), although I didn’t practice it so it was quite disjointed. Hopefully it wasn’t too bad in terms of the Mandarin usage, but I haven’t had any comments so maybe this platform isn’t going to be the best way forward. I’ll give it a bit more time before making that decision though.</p>

<h4 id="about-me">关于我 About Me</h4>

<p>[soundcloud url=”http://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/63535536” params=”color=3452d1&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true” iframe=”true” /]</p>

<p>My second clip was a recitation of a lullaby sung by Jackie Chan in the Spy Next Door (quite a funny film as it happens). I thought it sounded very gentle so I am now learning it to sing to George. This is the level I am at with it at the moment (this was read from a script as I can’t remember the words just yet :-)).</p>

<h4 id="ba-ma-de-hua">Ba Ma De Hua</h4>

<p>[soundcloud url=”http://api.soundcloud.com/tracks/65572317” params=”color=3452d1&amp;auto_play=false&amp;show_artwork=true” iframe=”false” /]</p>

<p>So both clips this month are a little disjointed, slow and hard to listen to, but it’s a start. I am aiming to do a lot more of this in future to improve the flow of my speaking. All in all I’m quite pleased so far.</p>

<h3 id="learn-at-least-200-new-characters-usingmemrisehttpwwwmemrisecom">4. Learn at least 200 new characters using <a href="http://www.memrise.com/">Memrise</a></h3>

<p> I tried really hard with this this month, but I missed a few days in the middle and have been trying to catch up every since. Still, I managed to get through nearly 150 new characters so I’m more than happy with that.</p>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>As I suspected, it still wasn’t a brilliant month for progress, but I think I’m definitely getting better so I am much happier than I was at the end of September. Instead of looking back at how I did this month, I am going to look forward to what I aim to do next month :-).</p>

<h4 id="plans-for-november">Plans for November</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Learn another 150 characters using <a href="http://www.memrise.com/">Memrise</a>;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Publish at least three audio clips to <a href="http://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a>;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>At least learn the words to <a href="http://soundcloud.com/richardpperry/ba-ma-de-hua">Ba Ma De Hua</a> by heart;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Complete the remaining lessons of <a href="http://www.pimsleur.com/Learn-Mandarin-Chinese">Pimsleurs</a> Mandarin 1.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mandarin Progress Month 1]]></title>
    <link href="/languages/mandarin-month-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T18:00:27Z</updated>
    <id>/languages/mandarin-month-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has now been a month since I started my Mandarin Chinese language challenge, so I think it’s time for an update on how I’m doing. To be honest, it’s not being going all that well. The first week went quite well, I was generally following my study plan (except for some evening sessions), but then it became unworkable. I guess I didn’t really plan it well enough, so I have amended the plan in an attempt to make it easier to follow without reducing the commitment needed. Well, it still isn’t really working. Here is a summary of the key points from this month.</p>

<p>[wpcol_1half]</p>

<h3 id="the-good">The Good</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I do listen to Mandarin radio most of the day in work;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I have kept up with my vocabulary on <a href="http://www.memrise.com">Memrise</a> (up to over 400 words now, although I did start that earlier this year).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>[/wpcol_1half][wpcol_1half_end]</p>

<h3 id="the-bad"> The Bad</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I haven’t been working on my Mandarin every day;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I still haven’t spoken to anyone yet (other than George &amp; myself);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I haven’t put much on my new Mandarin <a href="http://twitter.com/richard_p2_ZH">Twitter</a> account yet.[/wpcol_1half_end]</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Generally my commitment over the last month has been fairly poor for various reasons, but mainly because I am enjoying spending time with my son when I get home and by the time he goes to bed and we’ve eaten, I don’t feel like doing anything else. This is definitely not the right attitude if I want to improve so I am going to try to do better this month.</p>

<p>I will upload a video or audio clip of me speaking Mandarin in the next couple of days to show the progress I have/haven’t made.</p>

<h3 id="plans-for-october">Plans for October</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Practice more than twice a week;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Publish at least one journal entry to <a href="http://lang-8.com">Lang-8</a> per week;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Publish at least two audio clips to <a href="http://soundcloud.com/">Soundcloud</a>;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Learn at least 200 new characters using <a href="http://www.memrise.com">Memrise</a>.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Language Challenge]]></title>
    <link href="/languages/language-challenge/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-29T19:42:55Z</updated>
    <id>/languages/language-challenge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[caption id=”attachment_262” align=”alignleft” width=”150”]<a href="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/08/chinese_street_sign.jpg"><img src="http://richard.perry-online.me.uk/files/2012/08/chinese_street_sign-150x150.jpg" alt="Chinese Street Sign" /></a> Copyright © 2006 <a href="http://blog.teasetc.com/">Teas Etc - Tea Blog</a>[/caption]</p>

<p>Since early 2009 I have been learning Mandarin Chinese off and on. This may seem an odd language to choose so let me explain. In 2007 a good friend of ours told us about a Scouting trip he was organising to Russia, Mongolia &amp; China (further details available <a href="http://travel.perry-online.me.uk/trips/china-2009/">here</a>). This seemed like a good idea at the time, and, to cut a long story short, Rosie &amp; I decided to stay on in China for a further 5 weeks. The time we spent in China was absolutely amazing and I gained a real appreciation for the country, the culture and the language and I wanted to learn more.  I decided to learn the language to better understand the culture. Since then, it seems that my language learning has taken a bit of a back seat, with endless excuses rationalising why, so I have resolved to set up a language challenge to try to encourage me to get on with it!</p>

<p>The inspiration for this challenge came from Benny at <a href="http://www.fluentin3months.com/">Fluent in 3 Months</a>. At the start of this year he set out on his lofty goal of becoming fluent in Mandarin in 3 months. Although fluency wasn’t necessarily achieved in this time, he appears very comfortable conversing in Mandarin and this really has helped to spur me on. It was Benny who suggested that people should try their own <a href="http://www.fluentin3months.com/fi3m-challenge/">3 month challenge</a> over the summer, and although I’m a little late to the party (and adding a month) I am going to go for it :-). The challenge will run from 01 September 2012 until 31 December 2012 and the goals for this challenge are to be able to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>read 1,000 Chinese characters;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>have a simple 5 minute conversation with a Chinese speaker (probably via Skype);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>write simple sentences in Chinese, i.e. to Tweet in Chinese.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>This is all leading towards my long-term goals of being able to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>understand a film in Chinese;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>read a book in Chinese;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>converse confidently with Chinese speakers;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>teach my son rudimentary (at least) Mandarin.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>For this first language challenge, I am going to use the following resources:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.chinabooks.com/home.php?cat=319">New Practical Chinese Reader</a>  by Beijing Language &amp; Culture University Press (I picked this up in Chengdu in 2009);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.routledge.com/books/details/9780415434157/">Colloquial Chinese</a> by Qian Kan;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://memrise.com">Memrise</a> to learn the characters;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://chinesepod.com/">ChinesePod</a> for listening practice and to help learn sentence structures, grammar etc;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.pimsleur.com/Learn-Mandarin-Chinese">Learn Mandarin Chinese with The Pimsleur Method</a> for speaking &amp; listening;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="mms://media.ccdntech.com/wmtencoder/rti/cbs2.wmv">Chinese Radio</a> for real life listening practice;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://twitter.com/richard_p2_ZH">Twitter</a> for writing simple sentences regularly (new Chinese only Twitter account);</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.skype.com">Skype</a> for Language Exchanges;</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Any other suggestions would be gratefully received :-).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>This is going to need some serious commitment on my part, which has been a problem in the past. The main reason for this, I believe, is a lack of focus so I am going to put together a simple, flexible study planner allocating time slots to reading, writing, listening, speaking &amp; vocabulary work. It may take a while to get the balance right, but I think that combining time slots and a medium term challenge, I may actually achieve something tangible this time. I will try to track my progress with semi-regular updates on this blog.</p>

<p>Wish me luck :-P.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>